想象一下，我们现在想要尝试实现其中一些monadic操作，比如添加
Imagine now that we want to try and implement some of these monadic operations, like adding
每个像素的常数，或每个像素乘以常数。
a constant to every pixel, or to multiply every pixel by a constant.
一种方法是编写一些带有一些嵌套循环的代码
One way to do this would be to write some code with some nested loops that step through
矩阵中的每个元素并对它们执行monadic操作。
every element in the matrix and performs the monadic operation on them.
在MATLAB中有一种简单的方法，它是MATLAB中的一种技术
In MATLAB there is an easy way to do it and it is a technique in MATLAB that is referred
作为矢量化。
to as vectorization.
考虑到我们有一个包含n行和m列的矩阵，我们有一个标量。
Consider that we have a matrix with n rows and m columns and we have a scalar.
在中间我们有许多标准算术运算符;加，减，次，
And in in the middle we have a number of standard arithmetic operators; plus, minus, times,
分裂等等。
divide and so on.
例如，如果我们使用加法运算符加符号-我们将矩阵添加到标量中，
If, for instance, we use the addition operator—plus symbol—and we add the matrix to a scalar,
结果将是一个矩阵。
the result will be a matrix.
MATLAB要做的是将标量添加到每个元素中
And what MATLAB is going to do is to add the scalar to every individual element of the
输入矩阵并将其分配给输出矩阵中的相应元素。
input matrix and assign it to the corresponding element in the output matrix.
所以我们不必编写循环来将标量添加到每个元素中
So we do not have to write loops to go through and add the scalar to every element of the
输入矩阵。
input matrix.
MATLAB将为我们做，我们使用矩阵运算符和标量的简写符号。
MATLAB will do it for us, and we use the short hand notation of a matrix operator and a scalar.
所以我们可以为每个元素矩阵添加一个常量，减去常量;乘;划分;
So we can add a constant to every element matrix, subtract the constant; multiply; divide;
把每个元素都提升到一个力量;等等。
raise every element to a power; and so on.
我们现在将用一个真实的例子来证明这一点。
We are going to demonstrate this now with a real example.
我们将首先创建一个矩阵并将其命名为m，其元素将全部为整数，
We will start by creating a matrix and call it m, and its elements will all be integers,
1到10之间的整数。
integers between 1 and 10.
矩阵将是4乘4。
And the matrix will be 4 by 4.
我们将使用MATLAB内置的randi函数来随机创建这个矩阵
We are going to use MATLAB’s built in randi function to create this matrix with random
其中的整数元素。
integer elements in it.
现在我要向该矩阵添加1，或者添加一个矩阵-四乘四矩阵
Now I am going to add 1 to that matrix, or adding a matrix—four by four matrix—to
一个标量，MATLAB要做的是为矩阵的每个元素加1。
a scalar, and what MATLAB is going to do is add 1 to every element of the matrix.
同样，如果我将矩阵乘以2，我们将看到每个单独的元素
Similarly, if I multiply the matrix by 2, we will see that every individual element
在矩阵m中乘以2。
in the matrix m has been multiplied by 2.
我们可以以类似的方式执行更复杂的数学函数。
We can perform more complex mathematical functions in a similar way.
我们可以计算m的平方根，MATLAB要做的是计算平方
We can compute the square root of m, and what MATLAB is going to do is to compute the square
矩阵中每个元素的根。
root of every element within the matrix.
最后，我们可以将矩阵的每个元素提升到2的幂，我们使用运算符
Finally, we can raise each element of the matrix to the power of two, we use the operator
。^我们在这里看到的是矩阵m中的每个元素都已被平方。
.^ and what we see here is that every element in the matrix m has been squared.
重要的是要注意这与写这个非常不同，这是做了什么的
Important to note that this is very different to writing this, and what this has done is
将矩阵m乘以其自身;它和写那个一样。
to multiply the matrix m by itself; it is the same as writing that.
这是使用矩阵乘法规则将矩阵乘以矩阵-非常不同
This is multiplying a matrix by a matrix, using matrix multiplication rules — very different
将矩阵的每个元素提高到2的幂。
to raising each element of the matrix to the power of 2.